expatriates.com 2018-12-27

# expatriates.com - Privacy Statement

We created this privacy policy statement in order to show our firm commitment to your privacy. 

#### Introduction

Expatriates.com provides a bulletin board for classified ads accessible to any visitor. Please remember that any information you disclose in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

When placing an ad, we require your email address and a mobile phone number as an anti-fraud measure to ensure users are legitimate. Verifying your email and mobile phone number helps to prevent spam and scams from being perpetrated on the site. 

When browsing the site, we may log your IP address and store cookies for purposes such as customising content and advertising. 

We share information with our partners only to the extent necessary for the purposes of providing services to you. 

We use any information collected about you, to provide our services to you, to enable you to use our services, to browse and place classified ads, to analyze your use of our services, to detect fraud or other illegal activity and to improve our services. 

Aside from our partners who assist us in providing services to you and limited circumstances described below such as responding to law reinforcement requests, your personal information is confidential and we will it not make it available, under any circumstances, to third-parties. 

#### Placing a Classified Ad

Whenever you post a classified ad, your email address is required so that we may confirm your email address. The first time you place a classified ad we require you provide a mobile phone number. We need verify your email address and mobile phone number as an anti-fraud measure to ensure users are legitimate. 

We use Clickatell Inc as a service provider to send SMS messages to confirm your phone number. This is done as an anti-fraud measure to prevent spam or scams. As such Clickatell would have access to your phone number. Please see the Clickatell [ privacy policy](https://www.clickatell.com/legal/general-terms-notices/privacy-notice-2/) for further information. 

#### Logging

When browsing web pages on our site, our web logs track the current date,time and the IP address used. This logs are expunged every two weeks. 

#### Email Subscription

In our subscription form, we ask for your email address. We do not ask for any additional information. We use your email address to contact you when necessary and to send you classified ads in categories that you have requested. To unsubscribe you may use the unsubscribe form. To remove your published ads, you may request links to remove each ad using the following form. 

Your email address is confidential and we will it not make it available, under any circumstances, to commercial third-parties. 

#### Cookies and Web Beacons

In the course of paid ads being served on this web site, third parties may be placing and reading cookies on your browser, or using web beacons to collect information. 

If you wish to use our site and have cookies automatically deleted once you close you browser, you can use [private browsing](https://www.howtogeek.com/269265/how-to-enable-private-browsing-on-any-web-browser/) to do so. 

Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. 

It is possible to delete cookies for our site. Plesse find instructions below for deleting cookies for two popular web browsers. 

Google Chrome: [http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=95647](http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=95647)

Fire Fox: <http://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored#w_delete-cookies-for-a-single-site>

[

#### Advertising

](http://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored#w_delete-cookies-for-a-single-site)

[ We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, ](http://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/delete-cookies-remove-info-websites-stored#w_delete-cookies-for-a-single-site)[click here](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). 

If you do not want to see advertising, we recommend you install [ad blocking software](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ad_blocking) on your browser. You will be able to use the site and view its contents normally even with an ad blocker installed. 

#### Measuring Site Usage

We measure visitors to our website using Google Analytics. This records what pages you view within our site, how you arrived at our site and some basic information about your computer. All of that information is anonymous – so we don't know who you are; just that somebody visited our site. The information we collect from analytics helps us understand what parts of our sites are doing well, how people arrive at our site and so on. Like most websites, we use this information to make our website better. You can learn more about [Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html) or [opt out if you wish.](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)

#### Discussion Comments

To allow visitors to discuss classified ads, we use a discussion system called Disqus. To do so we embed code that Disqus provide and we do not control ourselves. Disqus anonymously tracks visitors to pages like we do. They also remember who you are if you login to any Disqus service, so you can comment on any website using their tool. Logging in to Disqus can be done in many ways, including via Facebook. If you login via social network, Disqus will be able to link your activity to that network. In this way, your Disqus activity may be personally identifiable. Disqus will know what pages you viewed in our site and what you wrote on those comments. Of course all comments you leave are also publicly visible on the Internet alongside your name, so we do not imagine this is a concern for many people. 

#### Online Payment

We use CCBill Inc as our payment provider should you decide to purchase a Premium ad. CCBill will have access to your personal and payment information. When paying by credit card, Expatriates.com themselves do not ever have any access to your credit card details. 

We share information with CCBill only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing payments you make via our website. 

#### Law Enforcement Requests

In order to enforce its terms of use, expatriates.com may dislose information about its users to law enforcement agencies or others. This is particularly the case if a user defrauds other expatriates.com users, deliberately places an ad impersonating another person, or publishes anothers person's private information. 

####  Updating Your Personal Information 

To remove your published ads, you may request links to remove each ad using the following form. 

Upon request, we will permanently delete your postings and all of your personal data. Our backup system will retain data for an additional 2 weeks before it is expunged permanently. 

#### Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, please send a message to [contact@expatriates.com](mailto:contact@expatriates.com).
